{
  "title": "4.6",
  "definitions": {
    "CONDEMN": {
      "word": "CONDEMN",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-dem')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to blame, criticize; to sentence, doom </p><p>To CONDEMN something is to declare that it is wrong or evil. CONDEMN is a very strong word and suggests complete disapproval. </p><p>“We all CONDEMNED his cruel treatment of the students.” </p><p>“She CONDEMNED the governor for his stand on taxes.” </p><p>To CONDEMN someone <i class=“def-ital\">to</i> something is to doom or sentence him to it. </p><p>“The judge CONDEMNED him to death.” </p><p>“His illness CONDEMNED him to a life spent in a wheelchair.” </p><p>The most common mistake in the Pretest is to choose <i class=“def-ital\">dislike</i> as the meaning of CONDEMN. CONDEMN is much stronger than <i class=“def-ital\">dislike</i>, however. You can <i class=“def-ital\">dislike</i> someone but not CONDEMN him. </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONDEMNATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "ENTERPRISE": {
      "word": "ENTERPRISE",
      "phonetic": "(en'-tÔøΩr-prlz)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an undertaking, project; a business, company; energy, daring, spirit </p><p>An ENTERPRISE is a project or undertaking, especially one that is risky or requires a great deal of skill or courage. </p><p>“Climbing MountbEverest is quite an ENTERPRISE.” </p><p>“Getting him up in the morning was a difficult ENTERPRISE.” </p><p>ENTERPRISE is also used for the spirit or energy which someone has to have to accomplish a challenging project. </p><p>“It took men of great ENTERPRISE to explore this jungle.” </p><p>ENTERPRISE is also another word for <i class=“def-ital\">business</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">company</i>. </p><p>“He owned a small but growing ENTERPRISE.” </p><p>“Free ENTERPRISE” is an economic system in which business projects can be undertaken with little restriction by the government. </p><p>Other forms of the word: ENTERPRISING, adj.</p>"
    },
    "MURAL": {
      "word": "MURAL",
      "phonetic": "(myUr'-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a wall painting </p><p>A MURAL is a painting done directly on a wall. The word MURAL comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">wall</i>. MURALS can also be large photographs or wallpaper scenes which are attached right to the wall, without a frame. </p><p>\"<i class=“def-ital\">The Last Supper</i> is a MURAL painted by Leonardo da Vinci.” </p><p>“The artist painted a colorful MURAL in the subway station.”</p>"
    },
    "REMNANT": {
      "word": "REMNANT",
      "phonetic": "(rem'-nÔøΩnt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a remainder, part left over </p><p>REMNANT is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">remain</i>. A REMNANT is a part left over, usually a very small or insignificant part. </p><p>“This painting is the only REMNANT of a once-huge art collection.” </p><p>“The enemy quickly captured the REMNANTS of the defeated army.” </p><p>“After the town burned down, people searched through the REMNANTS looking for survivors.” </p><p>A specific use of REMNANT is for a small piece of cloth left over after the larger part has been sold. </p><p>“The fabric store sold the REMNANTS at a greatly reduced price.”</p>"
    },
    "CORONATION": {
      "word": "CORONATION",
      "phonetic": "(kor-;}-nA'-shÔøΩn",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">the act of crowning </p><p>Corona is the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">crown</i>. A CORONATION is a crowning of a king, queen, or other ruler, with all the ceremonies that are part of the event. </p><p>“Many heads of state attended the CORONATION of the new king.” </p><p>“At Napoleon’s CORONATION he took the crown and placed it on his head himself.” </p><p>The most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">celebration</i>. There may be <i class=“def-ital\">celebrations</i> along with a CORONATION, but CORONATION has to do specifically with the crowning of a ruler.</p>"
    },
    "EMPLOY": {
      "word": "EMPLOY",
      "phonetic": "(em-ploy')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to use, make use of; to give work to </p><p>To EMPLOY something is to make use of it. </p><p>“He EMPLOYED every trick he knew, but he still couldn’t beat his opponent.” </p><p>“The grounds crew EMPLOYED a large helicopter to help dry off the field.” </p><p>To EMPLOY a person is to make use of his services, usually for pay. </p><p>“This factory EMPLOYS thousands of workers.” </p><p>“Bill is EMPLOYED by the insurance company to investigate accident claims.” </p><p>An EMPLOYER is a person or company who hires a worker, and an EMPLOYEE is a person who works for a company. </p><p>Other forms of the word: EMPLOYEE, n. EMPLOYER, n. EMPLOYMENT, n.</p>"
    },
    "GALA": {
      "word": "GALA",
      "phonetic": "(gA'-1:;,",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">festive, showy </p><p>GALA is both an adjective and a noun. As a noun it means “a special entertainment,” a <i class=“def-ital\">celebration</i>. </p><p>“All the leading society figures came to the GALA celebrating the opening of the museum.” </p><p>As an adjective the word means “like a GALA or celebration,” <i class=“def-ital\">festive</i>. </p><p>“His parties were always GALA occasions. Everyone loved to go to them.” </p><p>“It was a GALA day from beginning to end, with parades, games, plays, and all kinds of festivities.”</p>"
    },
    "OOZE": {
      "word": "OOZE",
      "phonetic": "(Uz)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to flow slowly, leak out </p><p>OOZE is the soft liquid mud at the bottom of a river or other body of water. To OOZE is to flow slowly like this mud, especially through small openings. </p><p>“Oil OOZED out of the crack in the engine.” </p><p>“Blood OOZED from the wound.” </p><p>OOZE can also mean to <i class=“def-ital\">give off</i>. </p><p>“His faced OOZED sweat as he tried to lift the trunk.” </p><p>The word can be used in a general sense about things and qualities besides liquids. </p><p>“She OOZED self-confidence as she strode into the room\"—that is, she had so much self-confidence that it seemed to flow out of her. </p><p>Many people think OOZE means to <i class=“def-ital\">overflow</i>. Both words are used about the flow of liquids, but OOZE means to <i class=“def-ital\">flow out slowly</i>.</p>"
    },
    "ORATION": {
      "word": "ORATION",
      "phonetic": "(8-rA'-sh:;,n)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a formal speech </p><p>An ORATION is a formal, dignified speech made on a public occasion. </p><p>“Marc Antony delivered a great ORATION at Caesar’s funeral.” </p><p>“The politician’s ORATION put most of the audience to sleep.” </p><p>An ORATOR is a person who makes such speeches. </p><p>“Daniel Webster was a great ORATOR. People would travel hundreds of miles to hear one of his speeches.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ORATOR, n. ORATORY, n.</p>"
    },
    "SATANIC": {
      "word": "SATANIC",
      "phonetic": "(s:;,-tan'-ik",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">devilish, wicked, evil </p><p>SATANIC is the adjective formed from SATAN, one of several names for the devil.  SATANIC means <i class=“def-ital\">wicked</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">evil</i>, like the devil. </p><p>“His SATANIC smile frightened everyone there.” </p><p>“Sometimes a truly SATANIC nature is hidden behind a mask of good manners.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Crazy</i> is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because SATANIC sounds a little like <i class=“def-ital\">moronic</i>.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ic</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "MULTITUDE": {
      "word": "MULTITUDE",
      "phonetic": "(muhl'-tg-tUd",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a crowd, a great number </p><p> MULTITUDE comes from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">many</i>, also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">multiply</i>. A MULTITUDE is a great number of something. </p><p>“This wonderful machine can do a MULTITUDE of jobs all at once.” </p><p>“There was a MULTITUDE of complaints about the new system of report cards.” </p><p>When used by itself, the word usually means “a great crowd of people.” </p><p>“A MULTITUDE had gathered to hear the president’s speech.”</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-tude</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "SHUN": {
      "word": "SHUN",
      "phonetic": "(shuhn)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to avoid, stay away from </p><p>SHUN means to <i class=“def-ital\">avoid</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">stay away from</i> something, usually because it is hateful, undesirable, or dangerous. You can SHUN both people and things. </p><p>“His friends SHUNNED him after they learned about his evil past.” “She SHUNS work whenever she can.” </p><p>“A hermit SHUNS the company of other people.”</p>"
    },
    "AGENDA": {
      "word": "AGENDA",
      "phonetic": "(g-jen'-dg)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an outline, program </p><p>An AGENDA is a list or outline of things to be done, a plan of procedure. Often a committee will organize its meetings around an AGENDA of subjects to be discussed or business to be carried out. </p><p>“The chairman made sure that every committee member received an AGENDA before each meeting.” </p><p>“The next item on the AGENDA is a discussion of how the money is to be spent.” </p><p>“My father called and wanted to know what was on our AGENDA for this weekend\"—that is, he wanted to know what we were planning to do.</p>"
    },
    "MATERNAL": {
      "word": "MATERNAL",
      "phonetic": "(m:rter'-ngl)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">motherly </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Mater</i> means <i class=“def-ital\">mother</i> in Latin. MATERNAL means “of or like a mother.”  </p><p>“She has MATERNAL feelings for her students. She treats them all like her children.” </p><p>“Her MATERNAL instincts told her that her children were in trouble.” </p><p>MATERNAL also means “on your mother’s side of the family.” Your MATERNAL grandfather is your mother’s father.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "STREW": {
      "word": "STREW",
      "phonetic": "(strU)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to spread, scatter, sprinkle </p><p>To STREW something is to spread it here and there over a surface. </p><p>“She STREWED the birdseed on the ground for the pigeons.” </p><p>STREW also means “to cover a surface with scattered things.” </p><p>“Pebbles STREW the surface of the road.” </p><p>The form STREWN is often used for what is called the <i class=“def-ital\">past participle</i> of STREW. </p><p>“The floor was STREWN with books and papers.” </p><p>“The child’s toys were STREWN over the room.”</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "6",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "They CONDEMN him.",
          "answers": [
            "overlook",
            "fear",
            "praise",
            "dislike",
            "blame"
          ],
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "blame"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A great ENTERPRISE.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "idea",
            "project",
            "trip",
            "mistake"
          ],
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "project"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Impressed by the MURAL.",
          "answers": [
            "small statue",
            "landscape",
            "photograph",
            "wall painting",
            "portrait"
          ],
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "wall painting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the REMNANT.",
          "answers": [
            "remainder",
            "difficulty",
            "result",
            "whole thing",
            "beginning"
          ],
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "remainder"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "During the CORONATION.",
          "answers": [
            "battle",
            "funeral",
            "crowning",
            "celebration",
            "speech"
          ],
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "crowning"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He EMPLOYED everything.",
          "answers": [
            "begged for",
            "used",
            "improved",
            "threw out",
            "started"
          ],
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "used"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GALA events.",
          "answers": [
            "famous",
            "theatrical",
            "dull",
            "feminine",
            "festive"
          ],
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "festive"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Began to OOZE.",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "leak slowly",
            "overflow",
            "slide",
            "boil away"
          ],
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "leak slowly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Impressive ORATION.",
          "answers": [
            "thought",
            "politician",
            "speech",
            "badge",
            "action"
          ],
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "speech"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SATANIC expression.",
          "answers": [
            "unfriendly",
            "devilish",
            "crazy",
            "saintly",
            "clever"
          ],
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "devilish"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the MULTITUDE.",
          "answers": [
            "heavens",
            "stars",
            "crowd",
            "beauty",
            "desert"
          ],
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "crowd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHUN these people.",
          "answers": [
            "dislike",
            "greet",
            "hurt",
            "fight",
            "avoid"
          ],
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "avoid"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Examined the AGENDA.",
          "answers": [
            "contents",
            "program",
            "article",
            "report",
            "office"
          ],
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "program"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MATERNAL interest.",
          "answers": [
            "undying",
            "feminine",
            "motherly",
            "family",
            "fatherly"
          ],
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "motherly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STREW the seeds.",
          "answers": [
            "pick",
            "find",
            "destroy",
            "spread",
            "want"
          ],
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "spread"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do judges CONDEMN people to prison?",
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a restaurant an ENTERPRISE?",
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a MURAL he outside?",
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a single tree be a REMNANT of a forest?",
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the president of the United States have a CORONATION when he enters office?",
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you EMPLOY a new worker?",
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a wedding celebration usually a GALA event?",
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can catsup OOZE?",
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an ORATION spoken?",
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a SATANIC person be frightening?",
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there a MULTITUDE of cars on the streets during a traffic jam?",
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you SHUN someone you're eager to see?",
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can there be several items on an AGENDA?",
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a person's MATERNAL aunt his mother's sister?",
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do neat people like to see things STREWN about?",
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "You shouldn't CONDEMN him just because he's not perfect.",
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was her ENTERPRISE that kept the business going.",
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He carried the MURAL around in his wallet to show people.",
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wrote himself a REMNANT that he had to go to the store after school.",
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After the young queen's CORONATION, there were parties throughout the city.",
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "My father is no longer EMPLOYED by the hardware store.",
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The Mardi Gras festival in New Orleans is a city-wide GALA.",
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The new father seemed to OOZE happiness as he showed us pictures of the baby.",
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His ORATION moved the audience to tears.",
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His SATANIC laughter made their blood run cold.",
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He complained about the MULTITUDE of problems he had to solve.",
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His father told Tom to SHUN the company of evil people.",
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wrote a complete AGENDA about what had happened at the meeting last week.",
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She took a MATERNAL interest in the girls in the club, treating them as she would her own daughters.",
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Two little girls walked in front of the bride and STREWED rose petals along the path.",
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CONDEMN",
          "answers": [
            "doom",
            "disbelieve",
            "criticize"
          ],
          "word": "CONDEMN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENTERPRISE",
          "answers": [
            "courage",
            "happiness",
            "business"
          ],
          "word": "ENTERPRISE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MURAL",
          "answers": [
            "design",
            "sculpture",
            "painting"
          ],
          "word": "MURAL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REMNANT",
          "answers": [
            "beginning",
            "trace",
            "fragment"
          ],
          "word": "REMNANT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CORONATION",
          "answers": [
            "enthronement",
            "crowning",
            "trip"
          ],
          "word": "CORONATION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMPLOY",
          "answers": [
            "use",
            "seek",
            "hire"
          ],
          "word": "EMPLOY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GALA",
          "answers": [
            "joy",
            "nervousness",
            "excitement"
          ],
          "word": "GALA",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OOZE",
          "answers": [
            "flood",
            "flow",
            "leak"
          ],
          "word": "OOZE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ORATION",
          "answers": [
            "talk",
            "song",
            "lecture"
          ],
          "word": "ORATION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SATANIC",
          "answers": [
            "criminal",
            "fiendish",
            "demonic"
          ],
          "word": "SATANIC",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MULTITUDE",
          "answers": [
            "several",
            "many",
            "few"
          ],
          "word": "MULTITUDE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHUN",
          "answers": [
            "switch",
            "escape",
            "evade"
          ],
          "word": "SHUN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AGENDA",
          "answers": [
            "list",
            "story",
            "plan"
          ],
          "word": "AGENDA",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MATERNAL",
          "answers": [
            "parental",
            "motherly",
            "childish"
          ],
          "word": "MATERNAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STREW",
          "answers": [
            "find",
            "sprinkle",
            "cover"
          ],
          "word": "STREW",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}